<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terraform on Chris ter Beke</title>
    <link>https://christerbeke.com/tags/terraform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Terraform on Chris ter Beke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 08:41:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://christerbeke.com/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A declarative approach for Dataflow Flex Templates</title>
      <link>https://christerbeke.com/posts/gcp-dataflow-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 08:41:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christerbeke.com/posts/gcp-dataflow-terraform/</guid>
      <description>This post originally appeared on Binx.io.
Google Cloud offers a managed Apache Beam solution called Dataflow. Since some time now Dataflow has a feature called Flex Templates. Flex Templates use Docker containers instead of Dataflow&amp;rsquo;s custom templates. The benefit is that Docker is a known standard and the container can run in different environments. However, a custom metadata JSON file is still needed to point to the Docker image in your registry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A minimal setup for a high availability service using Cloud Run</title>
      <link>https://christerbeke.com/posts/gcp-cloud-run-highly-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 08:41:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christerbeke.com/posts/gcp-cloud-run-highly-available/</guid>
      <description>This post originally appeared on Binx.io.
In this blog post, I will explain what is needed to set up a web service that runs in multiple GCP regions. The main reasons to deploy your service in more than one region are:
Handle single-region failures so that your application is highly available. Route traffic to the nearest region so your users experience faster loading times. Create Cloud Run deployments Link to heading A Cloud Run service only lives in a single region, so for a multi-region setup we will need to deploy the same container in multiple regions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
